<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>random on Raghavendra Kaushik</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/tags/random/</link><description>Recent content in random on Raghavendra Kaushik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rakaar.github.io/tags/random/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Useful discussions should be open</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-07-01-useful-discussions-open/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-07-01-useful-discussions-open/</guid><description>Suppose, you want to create an online group, where there is a scope for useful discussions. Useful discussions can include discussions about science, literature, art, poetry, programming, economics, books etc. Discussions that other like-minded might find interesting. Here is an opinionated request - create a sub-reddit for your discussions.
Generally, people prefer to create a Discord Server or a Slack Workspace. Because these tools really have a nice interface, that help make discussions easier.</description></item><item><title>The one aspect in which Humans are inferior to animals</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-06-25-meaninglessness/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-06-25-meaninglessness/</guid><description>Human beings are considered as the most complex forms of life, due to the activities that we have done and we are capable of. The current world that we see around proves the fact. We have built machines that help us communicate from one end of the world within seconds, do all sorts of other complex activities like Mathematics, literature, finding out the origin of universe and so on.
Yet, there is one simple thing that we humans have great difficulty in doing it when compared to animals.</description></item><item><title>Types of Science YouTubers</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-05-20-types-yt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-05-20-types-yt/</guid><description>Over the last 8 months, I have been exploring Physics. And I have explored and learnt most of the things from YouTube videos. The topics include Linear Algebra, basics of Special Relativity, Quantum Mechanics and many more. I was greatly amazed by the way YouTubers deliver the content, and how most of the learning becomes fun. The enthusiasm of fellow learners is reflected in the comment section of the videos and in sub-reddit posts.</description></item><item><title>On what to laugh?</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-04-18-on-what-2-laugh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-04-18-on-what-2-laugh/</guid><description>It happened to me several times, that I share a funny joke(funny according to me) with my friends and they get offended. This makes me feel guilty. Since, then I always used to wonder if there is any framework to decide if a joke is funny for everyone. When things like space and time are relative, how can you decide if something is funny or not absolutely?
But after reflecting on this, I came up with a small framework to decide if something is to be considered as a joke or taken seriously.</description></item><item><title>Adding Latex Support for math equations in your blog on Github Pages</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-12-02-addingmathjax/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-12-02-addingmathjax/</guid><description>If you have a blog, hosted on github pages where you adding your posts in markdown(like most of the blogs built using Jekyll have), here is how you can write math using latex in your blogs.
Step 1 In your _includes folder, create a file by name - mathjax.html and paste the content present here
The value of inlineMath key in the above code, means you must write your latex code between two $ symbols for example to write the famous Einstien&amp;rsquo;s enerngy mass equialent relation, you need to write something like this $E=mc^2$</description></item><item><title>Planning to restart writting</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-11-28-restart-blogging/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-11-28-restart-blogging/</guid><description>Why Suddenly? As holidays have come, there is a too much free time in hand. I am afraid that it might get wasted in useless things like spending too much time on YouTube, getting lost in random thoughts(generally happens during the college days). At the same time, I got to know about the fact that for a day, a human mind thinks of around 50,000 conscious thoughts. I still don&amp;rsquo;t trust the fact though!</description></item><item><title>Killing process with one command, which is still utilizing the port</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-07-28-killing-with-1-line/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-07-28-killing-with-1-line/</guid><description>Killing the process It happens regularly that when you stop the process(in my case mostly a node server or flask server) and restart in the same terminal session. It gives the error saying PORT is still in use. In that case, using ps aux and grep, you find the process id, and kill it. In this stackoverflow answer by Hamid Tavakoli. This simple one line does it for you
1 kill -9 $(ps aux | grep &amp;#39;\snode\s&amp;#39; | awk &amp;#39;{print $2}&amp;#39;) the above serves as an example for killing an node js process, which is still utilizing the port.</description></item><item><title>Writting to a file without using a file system library of that language</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-05-05-writing-to-a-file-without-using-file-system-lib/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-05-05-writing-to-a-file-without-using-file-system-lib/</guid><description>tee unix command Manytimes you want to write things to a file programmatically. That means, you write a code so as to fill the file. This involves importing the file system library in the respective language and using it. For example python and JS both use fs library. But there is a simpler way for super lazy people !
The idea is to just use the print the output and write the ouput to a file.</description></item></channel></rss>