<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blockchain on Raghavendra Kaushik</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/tags/blockchain/</link><description>Recent content in blockchain on Raghavendra Kaushik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rakaar.github.io/tags/blockchain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Endorsement Policies in Hyperledger Fabric</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-04-07-understanding-endorsement-policies-in-hf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-04-07-understanding-endorsement-policies-in-hf/</guid><description>Introduction Endorsement Policy defines which peers should execute a transaction and endorse its result(signing the execution result with its certificates) so as to consider the transaction to be valid. In other words, only after a set of peers endorse a transaction&amp;rsquo;s result then only the transaction will be committed in the ledger. This is my attempt to learn aspects of endorsement policy with more clarity
Where is it defined Well, endorsement policies can be defined at three different levels</description></item><item><title>Understanding Hyperledger fabric byfn setup briefly</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-04-04-hyperledger-fabric-understanding-byfn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-04-04-hyperledger-fabric-understanding-byfn/</guid><description>Introduction When I first go started with Hyperledger Fabric, it was a very daunting experience. All those yaml files, docker containers, commands, shell scripts confused a lot. Here in this article, I try to put those things very shortly on how a network is setup, mainly will consider the example of BYFN Hyperledger Fabric.
I am a beginner in the field. My sincere apologies to you, in case there are any errors or I failed to explain properly.</description></item><item><title>Monologue on Hyperledger Fabric</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-03-31-monologue-on-hyperledger-fabric/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-03-31-monologue-on-hyperledger-fabric/</guid><description>Public vs Private blockchains Blockchains when started out were open. Open in the sense, any individual can join the network, read , write and even verify the transactions. Also all the transactions that had happened in the blockchain would be visible to everyone in the network.
This type of model has been a great success for CryptoCurrencies and we have seen popular examples like Bitcoin and other alt coins. Ethereum is one such project which provides a platform to build Decentralised applications.</description></item><item><title>Mining and Proof of Work in Bitcoin</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2019-12-25-mining-and-proof-of-work-in-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2019-12-25-mining-and-proof-of-work-in-bitcoin/</guid><description>Introduction Pre-requisite: Basic understanding of Blockchain. More specifically, I will be talking about Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s mining. But it also applies to other cryptocurrencies following the same consensus protocol(we will see what that exactly means). My aim, while writing this is to provide some intuition behind proof of work algorithm and to explain in detail behind the puzzle that is solved by the miners in order to add a valid block to the Blockchain.</description></item></channel></rss>