<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>books on Raghavendra Kaushik</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/tags/books/</link><description>Recent content in books on Raghavendra Kaushik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rakaar.github.io/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Summaries of Aaron Swartz's selected blogs</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-06-11-aaronblogs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-06-11-aaronblogs/</guid><description>Aaron Swartz was a young hacktivist, who is popular for co-creating RSS, Reddit, CC license. On the activism side, he played a major role in preventing the Online Privacy act through SOPA. I have just mentioned the key points, to really know and understand Aaron&amp;rsquo;s Legacy, I highly recommend you to watch this documentary - The Internet&amp;rsquo;s own Child: The Story of Aaron Swartz. Aaron used to blog regularly on his site.</description></item><item><title>I read Notes from Underground</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-05-14-on-notes-from-underground/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-05-14-on-notes-from-underground/</guid><description>I recently read Notes from Underground by Dostoevsky. This is the second book I read of Dostoevsky. Crime and Punishment was my first. This is surprisingly a small around 120 page book, but contains a lot of practical philosophy, which I admit that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t grasp on my own when I read it. YouTube reviews on the book helped me understand things that I missed when I read it first. Nevertheless, there are some good things which I learned from the book.</description></item><item><title>Favourite ideas from the book - Man's search for meaning by Victor Frankl</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-03-16-man-meaning/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-03-16-man-meaning/</guid><description>Man&amp;rsquo;s search for meaning is a book by Victor Frankl, a holocaust survivor. Victor Frankl developed the concept of Logotherapy, in which neurosis(mental disorder involving stress) is treated by helping patient to find a meaning in his/her life, to live by. The first half of the book contains Author&amp;rsquo;s experiences and events in Auschwitz Concentration Camp. The author being a doctor, gives a psychological take on the events. Among these lines, there are many valuable and interesting ideas, and I wish to write a subset of them below.</description></item><item><title>Why you should read Einstein-His Life and Universe by Walter Isaacson</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-03-01-einstein-book/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-03-01-einstein-book/</guid><description>To summarize, it is one heck of a story, of how a simple patent clerk revolutionizes the way we think about world.
Why Einstein is a big deal: Einstein is a household name. During his era, he was treated as a Rockstar! He was undoubtedly most popular living physicist during his time. He was even offered the presidency of Israel, which he denied. After reading this book, you will really know what makes him so important.</description></item><item><title>Favourite ideas from Books that I read in 2020</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-02-27-2020-books/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-02-27-2020-books/</guid><description>When I learn about a new interesting idea present in a book, I read the book to explore the idea deeply and explore similar concepts and other ideas in the vicinity. In each book, there are some certain points which stay in my mind for a longer time and I try to put them into practice. In this blog, I wish to explain such ideas from the books that I have read in 2020.</description></item></channel></rss>