<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>deployment on Raghavendra Kaushik</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/tags/deployment/</link><description>Recent content in deployment on Raghavendra Kaushik</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rakaar.github.io/tags/deployment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Setting up Cirun on Digital Ocean</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-07-03-cirun/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2021-07-03-cirun/</guid><description>The problem Github Actions are amazing. They let you perform jobs on Github Cloud. But if you are using Github Actions too much, you might run out of the free minutes and you end up paying a lot. It is very likely that you are already paying for a cloud provider like AWS, Digital Ocean or Azure. So, a better idea would be to run the job on the existing cloud itself, instead of paying separately to run on Github cloud.</description></item><item><title>Automate deployment on an EC2 instance using Github Webhooks</title><link>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-07-12-automate-deploy/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rakaar.github.io/posts/2020-07-12-automate-deploy/</guid><description>Credits This article have been mainly inspired by the project -Midgard. Thanks to Pankaj Kumar with whom I setup this Continuous deployment. I am a newbie in this field of deployment. If any mistakes, please do provide a feedback. Also thanks to Shubham Mishra for helping us in the process.
Problem Statement There is a repository on github and you have an EC2 instance(or any instance provided by an IaaS). On every push to certain branch, you want the code in the instance to be updated.</description></item></channel></rss>